Ayush Kumar

Muzaffarpur, Bihar

ayush.singh095@gmail.com

+91-9472146033

linkedin.com/in/ayush-ksingh

https://ayush94k.github.io/

Summary

Professional having 7+ years of total experience, with 5 years in Project Management, MIS tools and Supply chain.

Experienced Professional trained in operation, PMBOK, MIS, Primavera and MS office.

Delivered 100% on Project Monitoring tool and MIS for 3 consecutive years.

Delivered 100% on Supply chain for 3 consecutive years.

My Aim it to play my part in developing the everchanging information technology systems present in our society.

Experience



🔀 Lead - Hub Operations (Hub Incharge)

Flipkart

Feb 2022 - Present (2 years)

- Accountable for all Marvel &Franchisee Operations under the span of control.
- Improving coverage through pincode expansion & reducing cost and 3PL dependency.
- Continue scouting of efficient local partners and stores.
- Ensure coordination to provide sufficient stationery/equipment's/essentials to partners/locations.
- Ensure availability of adequate and trained manpower and flexibility at all locations in BAU and peak.
- Ensuring Customers in the region are delighted at all times.
- Promptly and effectively manage customer escalations.
- Ensure 100% ZTP (Zero Tolerance Policy).
- Ensuring Local Deliverable are met and duly reported.
- Ensure all SOP & Compliance Adherence in the territory at all times.
- Proactively identify gaps in operations and support processes that impact operations and take preventive action.
- Responsible for Cash and shipment reconciliation of his nodes and territory.
- Ensure to monitor any financial loss to company and partner.
- Monitoring daily/weekly reports and take actions accordingly.



BBNL) Network Engineer

Bharat Broadband Network Limited

Mar 2019 - Jan 2022 (2 years 11 months)

Roles & Responsibility:

- Responsible for organizing and maintaining Project Management Tools & MIS Portal.
- Ensuring the use of project management tools by Vendors, auditors, CPSUs and SPSUs.
- Responsible for Preparation of daily/weekly/monthly progress report, scheduling of meeting, Preparation of PPT for meeting, Preparation of meeting agenda, taking meeting notes, Preparation of Minutes of Meeting and circulating it with the concerned officials of state government and central government.
- Coordinating the Site team and monitoring their performance.
- Planning and Monitoring of daily/weekly/monthly progress of 11 district of Jharkhand.

• Co-ordination with PIA, PMC and Third party auditors for O&M related activities to ensure end to end connectivity and acceptance tests.

Trainee

Power Grid Corporation of India Limited

Mar 2018 - Feb 2019 (1 year)

Roles & Responsibility:

- Co-ordination with vendor's team to ensure end to end connectivity.
- Plotting of OFC laying/Network diagram in Google earth based on physical survey.

Site Engineer

RUDRA INFRACITY PRIVATE LIMITED

Jun 2016 - Feb 2018 (1 year 9 months)

Roles & Responsibility:

- Preparing Progress reports based on the data shared by site team and design team.
- Co-ordination with Site Supervisor, design team and splicing team for O&M related activities to ensure end to end connectivity.

Vocational training

Indian Oil Corporation

Jun 2015 - Jun 2015 (1 month)

Vocational training of two weeks.



Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited

Dec 2013 - Jan 2014 (2 months)

Two week of In Plant Training at Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited Exchange, GMTD office.

Education



B.E., Electronics & control Engineering 2012 - 2016

Licenses & Certifications

- 🙀 Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Flipkart
- G The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing Google
- Cert Prep: Project Management Professional (PMP)® LinkedIn
- Cert Prep: Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician (100-105) LinkedIn

- Prepare for the CCNA Routing and Switching Certification LinkedIn
- in Building a Small Business Website with WordPress LinkedIn

Skills

Lean Six Sigma • Logistics Management • Supply Chain Management • Microsoft PowerPoint • Project Management • Telecommunications • HTML • Network Administration • Wide Area Network (WAN) • Internet Protocol (IP)

Honors & Awards

Best Employee - Audacity - Flipkart
Oct 2023

Best Kaizen of the year 2023 - Flipkart

Aug 2023

Awarded for the best Kaizen of the year 2023 Nationally.